Siinn Che

Address: 191 W. Woodruff Ave. Columbus, OH, 43210 • Phone: 510-967-5152 • Email: siinn.che@gmail.com

Blog: http://siinn.github.io • Github: github.com/siinn • Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/siinn-che

SUMMARY

Ph.D. student with extensive experience in **data analysis** with large experiment data at **CERN**. Experienced in data modeling, manipulation, and visualization with 5 years of experience in **Python** and C++. Strong background in **mathematics** and **statistics** from academic training. Enjoys working with others in a **collaborative** environment. Motivated to make a positive impact in **data science** with expertise in science research, academic training, and dedication to data science.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

CERN (The European Organization for Nuclear Research)

Geneva, Switzerland, 2013 - 2018

Graduate Researcher

- Data Analysis: Processed and analyzed large data (~200 TB) from ATLAS experiment with reduction rate < 5% in search for new physics.
- Data Mining: Developed a data mining algorithm to improve the efficiency of extracting rare physics data from 20% to over 90%.
- Modeling: Designed Monte Carlo simulation of complex physics processes using random sampling and statistical modeling.
- Visualization: Developed and implemented a visualization tool for experiment data at the Ohio State using Python Web App

LBNL (Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory)

Berkeley, CA 2009 - 2012

Research Associate

Modeling: Designed a simulation of complex molecular dynamics experiment using MATLAB

EDUCATION

Ph.D.	Experimental Particle Physics , The Ohio State University	2014 - 2017
	"Search for Long-lived Neutral Massive Particle with Displaced dilepton Resonance at the LHC"	
M.S.	Experimental Particle Physics, The Ohio State University	2012 - 2014
	"Higgs Boson as a Tool for Discovery at the LHC"	
B.A.	Mathematics & Physics, University of California, Berkeley	2007 - 2011
	Academic Achievement Scholarship Award, 2008, Linear Algebra (A+), Computational Physics (A)	

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

End-to-End Project:	NYC Rent Prediction: Regression models are built to predict apartment rent in NYC using RandomForest and
	GradientBoosting regressors using data collected by web scrapping. Two regression models are compared using learning
	curves and cross-validation metrics.
Selected Kaggle Project	Recognizing hand-written digits: Analyzed and classified images of hand-written digits from MNIST dataset using Principal
	component analysis (PCA) and unsupervised learning (K-Mean clustering).
In-course Projects	Natural language processing, Recommender system, SVM, Geographical Plotting.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data science	Python (pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, matplotlib, seaborn), SQL.
Machine Learning	Scikit-learn (model selection, regression, classification, clustering, PDA).
Research	C++, ROOT statistics package, Distributed computing.
Development Environment	UNIX (bash, ssh), svn, Github , LaTex, Jupyter notebook.